<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alex Reis</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alex Reis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simultaneous repression of many bacterial genes using nonrepetitive extra-long sgRNA arrays</title>
      <link>/posts/elsas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/elsas/</guid>
      <description>Synthetic biologists, our group included, have been drawn by the power of CRISPR technologies1 to completely revolutionize how we program cell behavior, for example, by designing programmable CRISPR-based genetic circuits. Genetic circuits, like digital ones, take input signals from the surrounding environment (e.g. relevant biologics, chemicals, temperature, UV), and through a series of logic gates, perform computation or “signal processing”, with useful output that can be read out or passed to biological actuators within a programmed cell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multiplex test for diagnosing respiratory virus infections simultaneously in 10,000 patients</title>
      <link>/posts/multiplex-sarscov2-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/multiplex-sarscov2-concept/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few weeks of the COVID-19 pandemic, limited availability and throughput of the existing COVID-19 test kit has hindered our ability to monitor the global spread of the causal virus, SARS-CoV-2. As of March 24nd, the CDC reported having only tested 4,651 and 83,391 patients across the U.S. in CDC and public health laboratories, respectively, since January 18th &amp;ndash; with the bulk of those tests done within the past week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD student in the Chemical Engineering department at Penn State University studying synthetic biology. My work includes modeling efforts to predict gene expression levels, developing scaled systems to simultaneously regulate dozens of genes in vivo, and developing other assorted biotechnologies for areas including energy, materials, and medicine. The connective tissue behind these seemingly different projects is the study and application of fundamental biophsyical principles, such as nucleic acid sequence-to-function relations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Hossain, A., Lopez, E., Halper, S. M., Cetnar, D. P., Reis, A. C., Strickland, D., &amp;hellip; &amp;amp; Salis, H. M. (2020). Automated design of thousands of nonrepetitive parts for engineering stable genetic systems. Nature biotechnology, 1-10. [link]
  Reis, A. C., Halper, S. M., Vezeau, G. E., Cetnar, D. P., Hossain, A., Clauer, P. R., &amp;amp; Salis, H. M. (2019). Simultaneous repression of multiple bacterial genes using nonrepetitive extra-long sgRNA arrays.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>