<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Copyright 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A multiplex test for diagnosing respiratory virus infections simultaneously in 10,000 patients</title>
      <link>/posts/multiplex-sarscov2-concept/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/multiplex-sarscov2-concept/</guid>
      <description>Over the last few weeks of the COVID-19 pandemic, limited availability and throughput of the existing COVID-19 test kit has hindered our ability to monitor the global spread of the causal virus, SARS-CoV-2. As of March 24nd, the CDC reported having only tested 4,651 and 83,391 patients across the U.S. in CDC and public health laboratories, respectively, since January 18th &amp;ndash; with the bulk of those tests done within the past week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a PhD Graduate Student in the Chemical Engineering department at Penn State University studying synthetic biology, helping mature the field into a full-fledged engineering discipline. My work includes modeling efforts to predict gene expression levels1, developing scaled systems to simultaneously regulate dozens of genes in vivo2, and developing other assorted biotechnologies for energy, materials, and medicine. The connective tissue behind these seemingly different projects is the application of fundamental biophysical principles and an understanding of nucleic acid sequence-to-function relations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>